Guide to the Naum Gabo Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1939-1980; Series I; 16.06; (40 boxes)
  - General Correspondence
    - Matisse, Pierre, 2 (Box 17)
    - Mattatuck Museum, Waterbury, CT (Box 17)
    - May, Mrs. Saidie, 3 (Box 17)
    - Mazur, Michael (Box 17)
    - Mechanics Savings Bank, CT (Box 17)
    - Medicare, 6 (Box 17)
    - Meier, Professor Norman C. (Box 17)
    - Mellis, Margaret (Box 17)
    - Meriden Gravure Co., CT (Box 17)
    - Metropolitan Museum, New York (Box 17)
    - Meyer, Dr. E. Michael (Box 17)
    - Meyer, Hannes (Box 17)
    - Middelheim Promotors, Antwerp, Belgium (Box 17)
    - Middlebury Fund (Box 17)
    - Midland Bank (Box 17)
    - Mies Van Der Rohe, Ludwig (Box 17)
    - Miller, Arthur (Box 17)
    - Miller, Henry (Box 17)
    - Miller, Stephen (Box 17)
    - Milner, John (Box 17)
    - The Modern Institute of Art, San Francisco (Box 17)
    - Moderna Museet, Stockholm, 3 (Box 17)
    - Moholy-Nagy, L. (Box 17)
    - Moholy-Nagy, Sibyl (Box 17)
    - Monagan, John S., 5 (Box 17)
    - Monshouwer, Fritz (Box 17)
    - Morgehan, Professor (Box 17)
    - Morton, Alastair (Box 17)
    - Moore, Sir Henry (Box 18)
    - Moore, Lamont and Henrietta (Box 18)
    - Morley, Grace L. McCann (Box 18)
    - Morris, George L.K., 3 (Box 18)
    - Morris, William (Box 18)
    - Morse, Marston (Box 18)
    - Muche, George (Box 18)
    - Mulhausen, Knud (Box 18)
    - Mullins, Edwin (Box 18)
    - Mumford, Alison (Box 18)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 20 (Box 18)
    - Mumford, Sophia, 4 (Box 18)
    - Mundus Artium, Ohio University (Box 19)
    - Munson, Williams, Proctor Institute (Box 19)
    - Murray Hill Travel Service (Box 19)
    - Musee de Peinture et Sculpture, Grenoble, 3 (Box 19)
    - Musee des Arts Decoratifs, Paris (Box 19)
    - Musee des Ecoles Etrangeres Contemporaines, Paris (Box 19)
    - Musee National d'Art Moderne, Paris, 4 (Box 19)
    - Musee Rodin, Paris (Box 19)
    - Museum of Art of Ogonquit (Box 19)
    - Museum of Contemporary Art, Chicago (Box 19)
    - Museum of Modern Art, New York, 22 (Box 19)
    - Nakov, Andre Boris (Box 20)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Washington (Box 20)
    - National Collection of Fine Arts (Box 20)
    - National Gallery of Art, Washington, 3 (Box 20)
    - National Gallery of Art, Canberra, Australia, 3 (Box 20)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 8 (Box 20)
    - Needham, Gerald (Box 20)
    - Nerdinger, Winfried (Box 20)
    - Netherlands Art Foundation (Box 20)
    - Netherlands Information Service (Box 20)
    - Newburger, Hanna L. (Box 20)
    - New Britain Museum of American Art (Box 20)
    - Newman, R. (Box 20)
    - Newton, Eric (Box 20)
    - The New York Times (Box 20)
    - New York Trust Company (Box 20)
    - New York University: incl. Grey Art Gallery and Study Center (Box 20)
    - Nicholson, Ben, 2 (Box 20)
    - Nicholson, Winifred (Box 20)
    - Nord-Rhein-Westfalen Kulturminister, Dusseldorf, 3 (Box 20)
    - Norman, Dorothy (Box 20)
    - North Carolina State College, 2 (Box 20)
    - Northern Architectural Students Association (Box 20)
    - Norton, Peter (Box 20)
    - Nueva Vision, Editorial (Box 20)
    - Nurnberg, Kunsthalle (Box 20)
    - Na-Nd General (Box 20)
    - Ne-N General (Box 20)
    - No-Nz General (Box 20)
    - Odams Press (Box 20)
    - L'Oeil, Paris (Box 20)
    - Office de Radiodiffusion - Television Francaise (Box 20)
    - Office Service Company (Box 20)
    - O'Konor, Louise (Box 20)
    - Osborn, Robert and wife Elodie, 2 (Box 20)
    - Oslo Holmenkollen Turist Hotel (Box 20)
    - Oslo: Munch Museum Kummunes Kunstsamlinger, 8 (Box 20)
    - Oslo - Sonja Henie-Niels Onstad Foundations, 3 (Box 21)
    - Oslo University, 2 (Box 21)
    - O General (Box 21)
    - Parsons: Betty Parsons Gallery, New York (Box 21)
    - Pasadena Art Museum (Box 21)
    - Pasmore, Victor (Box 21)
    - Passport Office, London (Box 21)
    - Pattison, Frederick Woodworth (Box 21)
    - Pegasus Bookshop, Amsterdam, 2 (Box 21)
    - Pellegrini and Cudamy, New York (Box 21)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 2 (Box 21)
    - Penrose, Sir Roland (Box 21)
    - Galerie Percier (Box 21)
    - Pertzoff, Constantin A. (Box 21)
    - Pertzoff, Ira (Box 21)
    - Pertzoff, Olga (Box 21)
    - Pertzoff, Tanya (Box 21)
    - Phillips Collection (Box 21)
    - Philosophical Library, New York (Box 21)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 2 (Box 21)
    - Pittsburgh - Carnegie Institute of Technology (Box 21)
    - Pittsburgh - Carnegie Institute Department of Fine Art (Box 21)
    - Pittsburgh - Museum of Art, Carnegie Institute (Box 21)
    - Plastics, London (Box 21)
    - Podarogifts Inc., New York, 5 (Box 21)
    - Poetry London, 3 (Box 21)
    - Portland Art Museum (Box 21)
    - Prague National Gallery (Box 21)
    - Pratt Institute, Brooklyn (Box 21)
    - Princeton University, 3 (Box 21)
    - Pritchard, Jack and Molly (Box 21)
    - Probst: Neve Kunst Fides, Dresden (Box 21)
    - Public Broadcast Laboratory (Box 21)
    - Pujmanova, Olga (Box 21)
    - Pulsford, Madge (Box 21)
    - Pa-Pd General (Box 21)
    - Pe-Pm General (Box 21)
    - Pi-Pz General (Box 21)
    - Radcliffe Institute, Cambridge (Box 22)
    - Ragon, Michel (Box 22)
    - George Rainbird Ltd., London (Box 22)
    - [Ramsden?], Hartley, 4 (Box 22)
    - Rannit, Aleksis (Box 22)
    - Ratcliffe, Edward (Box 22)
    - Rathke (Box 22)
    - Read, Sir Herbert, 17 (Box 22)
    - Read, Piers Ben, Thomas, Sophie (Box 22)
    - Read, Lady, 3 (Box 22)
    - Rebay, Hilla (Box 22)
    - Reddihough (Box 22)
    - Redfern Gallery, London (Box 22)
    - Redstone, Louis G. (Box 22)
    - Reid, Jean (Box 22)
    - Reis, Becky (Box 22)
    - Reis, Bernard (Box 22)
    - Reneuf, Edda (Box 22)
    - Reneuf, Edward and Catherine (Box 22)
    - Reutlinger, A.S. (Box 22)
    - Rhode Island School of Design, 3 (Box 22)
    - Richman, Robert, 8 (Box 22)
    - Richman, Maida and Robert, 2 (Box 22)
    - Richter, Friedl, 4 (Box 23)
    - Richter, Hans, 3 (Box 23)
    - Rickey, Edith, 4 (Box 23)
    - Rickey, George, 2 (Box 23)
    - John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art, Sarasota, Florida (Box 23)
    - Roberson, Richard (Box 23)
    - Roche, H.P. (Box 23)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 6 (Box 23)
    - Rogers, Richard and Susan (Box 23)
    - Rosenberg, Eugene (Box 23)
    - Rossabi, Mary (Box 23)
    - Rothschild, Herbert M. (Box 23)
    - Rotterdam, Museum Boymans, 2 (Box 23)
    - Rothschild, Jacob (Box 23)
    - Royal College of Art, London, 3 (Box 23)
    - Royal Swedish Academy of Fine Arts (Box 23)
    - Roys, Margaret (Box 23)
    - Royal Institute of British Architects (Box 23)
    - Ruel, Leslie (Box 23)
    - Ra-Rh General (Box 23)
    - Ri-Ror General (Box 23)
    - Ros -Rz General (Box 23)
    - Saarinen, Eero (Box 24)
    - Sage, Kay (Box 24)
    - Sainsbury, Sir Robert and Lady (Lisa) (Box 24)
    - Salisbury, Harrison (Box 24)
    - San Francisco Bay Exposition (Box 24)
    - San Francisco Civic Center Plaza International Competition (Box 24)
    - San Francisco, Golden Gateway Competition (Box 24)
    - San Francisco Museum of Art, 3 (Box 24)
    - Sandberg, Willelm, 10 (Box 24)
    - Sanders, Pieter (Box 24)
    - Sanders, Paul (Box 24)
    - Sandved, Kjell (Box 24)
    - Santini (Box 24)
    - Scammel, Michael (Box 24)
    - Schapiro, Alma (Box 24)
    - Schapiro, Professor Leonard (Box 24)
    - Schawinsky, Xanti (Box 24)
    - Scheer, Dr. A. (Box 24)
    - Schipper, Merle (Box 24)
    - Schmalenbach, Dr. Werner (Box 24)
    - Schmierer, Martha (Box 24)
    - Schmidt, Dale (Box 24)
    - Schonbauer, Henry (Box 24)
    - Schreiber-Ruffer, Margarete (Box 24)
    - Schreyer, Leslie J. (Box 24)
    - Schubert, Mary (Box 24)
    - Schultz, Fred (Box 24)
    - Schwartz, Arthur Gallerie e Libraria d'Arte, Milan (Box 24)
    - Schwartz, Dr. Karl (Box 24)
    - Schweicher, Dr. C. (Box 24)
    - Schwitters, Kurt (Box 24)
    - Scollar, Irwin (Box 24)
    - Scoville, Thomas (Box 24)
    - Scully, Vincent (Box 24)
    - Seattle, Central Association of Seattle (Box 24)
    - Seelig, Carl (Box 24)
    - Seiberling, Frank (Box 24)
    - Selz, Jean (Box 24)
    - Semjonov, Jurii, 2 (Box 24)
    - Senter, Terrence (Box 24)
    - Sert, Jose Luis (Box 24)
    - Setik, Dr. Jiri (Box 24)
    - Seuphor, Michel, 2 (Box 24)
    - Shankland, Graeme (Box 24)
    - Shephard, Sheldon (Box 24)
    - Sherman, Paul (Box 24)
    - Sztein, Emmanuel (Box 24)
    - Sihare, L.P. (Box 24)
    - Sisson, Molly (Box 24)
    - Sisson, Richard and Roberta (Box 24)
    - Sjoberg, Leif, 7 (Box 24)
    - Skira Publishers (Box 24)
    - Slavic Review, Columbia University, New York (Box 24)
    - Smith, Richard (Box 24)
    - Smith College, Northampton, Massachusetts (Box 24)
    - The Smithsonian Institution, Washington (Box 24)
    - Soby, James T. (Box 24)
    - Societe des Artistes de France, Paris (Box 24)
    - Soeppert, Louise (Box 24)
    - Sole-Leris, Amadeo (Box 24)
    - Solley, Thomas T. (Box 24)
    - Southhampton College, Long Island University (Box 24)
    - Southern Railway Britain (Box 24)
    - J.B. Speed Art Museum, Louisville (Box 24)
    - Spencer, Marianne (Box 24)
    - Spencer, Ruth (Box 24)
    - Spender, Stephen (Box 24)
    - St. Ives Society of Artists (Box 25)
    - St. Louis, City Art Museum, 5 (Box 25)
    - St. Margaret's School, Waterbury, 4 (Box 25)
    - St. Mary's College, Maryland (Box 25)
    - Stadtische Kunsthalle, Mannheim (Box 25)
    - Staempli Gallery, New York (Box 25)
    - Staley, Alan (Box 25)
    - Starr, Frederick (Box 25)
    - State of Connecticut: Department of Motor Vehicles (Box 25)
    - Stedelijk Museum, Amsterdam, 10 (Box 25)
    - Steinitz, Kate (Box 25)
    - Steneberg, E. (Box 25)
    - Stern (Box 25)
    - Stillman, Rufus (Box 25)
    - Stockholm, Broadcast (Box 25)
    - Stockholms, Stad. Gatukontor, 2 (Box 25)
    - Stokes, Adrian (Box 25)
    - Stokes, Telfer (Box 25)
    - Stone, Katherine (Box 25)
    - Stone, Peter (Box 25)
    - Strasbourg, Musees de la Ville (Box 25)
    - Strawson, Frank (Box 25)
    - Strawson, Vera, 2 (Box 25)
    - The Structurist, Saskatoon, Canada (Box 25)
    - "Studio International", London, 2 (Box 25)
    - Sutherland, Helen (Box 25)
    - Sutro Brothers and Co. (Box 25)
    - Svenska Fysikeramfundet (Swedish Physical Society) (Box 25)
    - Sveriges Radio (Box 25)
    - Swanson, Donald (Box 25)
    - Sweeney, James Johnson, 6 (Box 25)
    - Syracuse University (Box 25)
    - Sa-Sc General (Box 25)
    - Se-Sh General (Box 25)
    - Si-Sk General (Box 25)
    - Sl-Sn General (Box 25)
    - So-Ss General (Box 25)
    - St-Sz General (Box 25)
    - Tarica (Box 26)
    - Tate Gallery, London, 19 (Box 26)
    - Taute, Horst and Ella (Box 26)
    - Tavistock Publications, London (Box 26)
    - Tempo, London (Box 26)
    - Thames and Hudson, London (Box 26)
    - Thiel (Box 26)
    - Thomas, Neal (Box 26)
    - Thwaites, John Anthony (Box 26)
    - Time (Time and Life) Magazine (Box 26)
    - Alec Tiranti Limited (Box 26)
    - Tobey, Mark (Box 26)
    - Toorop, Charles (Box 26)
    - Topliss and Harding (Box 26)
    - Torrance, Walter (Box 26)
    - Tourtelot, Madeline (Box 26)
    - Tremaine (Box 26)
    - Trier, Eduard (Box 26)
    - Trinity College, Hartford (Box 26)
    - Tschichold, Jan (Box 26)
    - Truman, Jock (Box 26)
    - Tyler and Co., London (Box 26)
    - Tzara, Tristan (Box 26)
    - Ta-Th General (Box 26)
    - Ti-Tz General (Box 26)
    - Union Tours, 3 (Box 26)
    - United Hias Service (Box 26)
    - United Service for New Americans (Box 26)
    - United States Department of Justice, 4 (Box 26)
    - United States Department of State (Box 26)
    - Universita Internazionale Dell'Arte Firenze, Venezia (Box 26)
    - United States Embassy, Lisbon (Box 26)
    - University College, London (Box 26)
    - University of California, Santa Barbara (Box 26)
    - University of Illinois (Box 26)
    - University of Kentucky (Box 26)
    - University of Saskatchewan (Box 26)
    - University of Southern California, Los Angeles (Box 26)
    - University of Texas at Austin (Box 26)
    - USSR Embassy, London (Box 26)
    - U General (Box 26)
    - Chicago - Art Institute (Box 27)
    - Van Der Wal, G. (John and Janna), 2 (Box 27)
    - Van Traa, Dr. (Box 27)
    - Vassar College (Box 27)
    - Venice Biennale (Box 27)
    - Ventris, Dorothea (Box 27)
    - Ventris, Lois (Betty), 4 (Box 27)
    - Ventris, Michael, 2 (Box 27)
    - Ventris, Nikki (Box 27)
    - Ventris, Tessa (Box 27)
    - Verlag Gerd Hatje, Stuttgart (Box 27)
    - Viking Press, New York, 3 (Box 27)
    - Villanueva, Carlos Raul, 2 (Box 27)
    - "Vingtieme Siecle" XXe Siecle, Paris (Box 27)
    - Virginia Education Association (Box 27)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, Richmond, 2 (Box 27)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute (Box 27)
    - Volochova, Sonia (Box 27)
    - Va-Vz General (Box 27)
    - Wade-White, Elizabeth, 2 (Box 27)
    - Wade-White, Henry, 2 (Box 27)
    - Wadsworth Atheneum, Hartford, 4 (Box 27)
    - Walbridge, Norton S. (Box 27)
    - Walenciak, Boris (Box 27)
    - Walker Art Center, Minneapolis (Box 27)
    - Wallenstam, Lennart (Box 27)
    - Washington University, St. Louis, Missouri (Box 27)
    - Waters and Co., London (Box 27)
    - Weatherby, Meredith (Box 27)
    - Webb, Susan and Kenneth (Box 27)
    - Weiss, Lotte (Box 27)
    - Wells, John (Box 27)
    - Wellesley College, Massachusetts (Box 27)
    - Wesleyan University, Davison Art Center, Middletown, Conn. (Box 27)
    - Western Illinois University (Box 27)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, New York, 6 (Box 28)
    - Whitney, Thomas P., 5 (Box 28)
    - Whyte, Lancelot L. (Box 28)
    - Wiedler, Charlotte (Box 28)
    - William Pall Gallery, New York (Box 28)
    - Wilson, Charles (Box 28)
    - Winfield, Armand G. (Box 28)
    - Winter, Fritz (Box 28)
    - Wistar Institute, Philadelphia (Box 28)
    - Wittenborn and Co., 2 (Box 28)
    - Wolff, Kurt (Box 28)
    - Wolff, Robert Jay (Box 28)
    - Woodbury, Woman's Club (Box 28)
    - The Woog Institute Collection of Art, Geneva (Box 28)
    - Worcester Art Museum (Box 28)
    - Wornum, Miriam, 3 (Box 28)
    - Wornum, Michael (Box 28)
    - Wright, Lisa and Martin (Box 28)
    - Writers and Artists Protest (Box 28)
    - Wa General (Box 28)
    - Wb-We General (Box 28)
    - Wf-Wi General (Box 28)
    - Wj-Wz General (Box 28)
    - Yakobson, Roman (Box 28)
    - Yale University Art Gallery, New Haven, 4 (Box 28)
    - Yale University Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library (Box 28)
    - Yale University Department of Architecture (Box 28)
    - Yale University Library and Art Library (Box 28)
    - Yale University Division of the Arts - Yale School of Fine Arts (Box 28)
    - Yale University School of Art and Architecture (Box 28)
    - Yale University Russian Club (Box 28)
    - Yale University Misc. (Box 28)
    - Y General (Box 28)
    - Young Men and Young Women's Hebrew Association (Box 28)
    - Zervos (Box 28)
    - Zoll, Susan and Steve (Box 28)
    - Zuckermann, Solly and Joan (Box 28)
    - Zurich, Kunsthaus (Box 28)
    - Z General (Box 28)
  - Dictations
    - Miriam Gabo's Stenographic Notebooks, 1939-1945, undated; 10 (Box 29)
    - Miriam Gabo's Stenographic Notebooks, 1943-1948, undated; 10 (Box 30)
  - Projects
    - Bijenkorf Construction, Rotterdam, 1954-1961, undated; 25 (Box 31)
    - Exhibition in America (Box 32)
    - Contracts (Box 32)
    - The Circle, 7 (Box 32)
    - 1938 US Exhibition (Box 32)
    - Esso Project, 7 (Box 32)
    - Wrenn, Lewis and Jencks, 2 (Box 32)
    - Art Commission for South Mall Project, Albany (Box 32)
    - St. Thomas' Fountain, 6 (Box 32)
  - Family
    - Bauman, Irma (Box 33)
    - Franklin, Cyril (Box 33)
    - Franklin, Joseph (Box 33)
    - Franklin, Owen (Box 33)
    - Franklin, Roger and Beverly (Box 33)
    - Franklin, Mrs. (Box 33)
    - Franklin (grandchildren of Miriam Gabo) (Box 33)
    - Gabo, Miriam (Box 33)
    - Gabo, Nina, 3 (Box 33)
    - Gilman, Anna (Box 33)
    - Goodale, Grace (Box 33)
    - Israels, Carlos, 4 (Box 33)
    - Israels, Joseph, 2 (Box 33)
    - Israels, Michael (Box 33)
    - Perry, Elizabeth (Box 33)
    - Pevsner, Aleksei, 4 (Box 33)
    - Pevsner, Antoine, 2 (Box 33)
    - Pevsner, Mark (Box 33)
    - Pevsner, Virgine (Box 33)
    - Richter-Gabo, Elizabeth, 5 (Box 33)
    - Vas, Katya (Box 33)
  - Unsorted Correspondence
    - Misc. and unidentified letters of condolence (Box 34)
    - A-Z letters of condolence, 5 (Box 34)
    - Misc.: Fan or Nuisance mail, 5 (Box 34)
    - International Chemical Industries, 11 (Box 35)
    - Sisson, John, 5 (Box 35)
    - Mats (Box 36)
    - Materials, Misc., 2 (Box 36)
    - Materials M&B Plastics (Box 36)
    - Materials: "Gabo's first Power Tool", Churchill & Co. (Box 36)
    - Harold Heydon & Co. Ltd. (Box 36)
    - Materials: Plywood Hills and Board of Supply (Box 36)
    - Materials: Kenneth Lynch Inc. (Box 36)
    - Ambrozatis, Joseph (Box 36)
    - Anaconda American Brass Co., Waterbury (Box 36)
    - Materials: Cellon Ltd, Surrey (Box 36)
    - Chase Brass and Copper Company, Waterbury (Box 36)
    - Chemical Development Corporation (Box 36)
    - Materials: Cold Spring Granite Co. (Box 36)
    - Commercial Plastics, Orange (Box 36)
    - Materials: Connecticut Metal Finishing Company (Box 36)
    - Connecticut Spring Company (Box 36)
    - Cook, Dunbar, Smith and Co. (Box 36)
    - Materials: Coopersburg Granite Co. (Box 36)
    - Dupont Plastics (Box 36)
    - Dura Plastics (Box 36)
    - Eastman Chemical Products (Box 36)
    - Materials: Henriques, J.B. And Co. (Box 36)
    - J. Hewitt and Sons, Ltd., London (Box 36)
    - Holtzer-Cabot (Box 36)
    - Hurst Manufacturing Company (Box 36)
    - Industrial Steels Inc. (Box 36)
    - Materials Processing etc.: Lukens Steel Co. (Box 36)
    - Materials: Merkle-Korff Gear Co. (Box 36)
    - Metallizing Service Company, 2 (Box 36)
    - Modern Art Foundry, Long Island City (Box 36)
    - Materials: Owens Corning Fiberglass Corporation (Box 36)
    - Materials: Phoenix-Apollo Steel Co. (Box 36)
    - Rohm and Haas, Philadelphia (Box 36)
    - Morris Singer Foundry, 2 (Box 36)
    - Spink and Gaborg Inc. (Box 36)
    - Materials, Processes: J. Starkie Gardner (Box 36)
    - Materials and Models: Steiner Plastics (Box 36)
    - Materials Etc.: Taunton Engineering Works (Box 36)
    - Materials: Templeman, The D.R. Templeman Co., Springs, Plainville CT, 2 (Box 36)
    - Materials: Templeton, Charles A., 4 (Box 36)
    - Materials: Tiranti and Co., London (Box 36)
    - Materials: Tyler, The W.S. Tyler (Box 36)
    - Materials: United States Steel (Box 36)
    - Wallace Barnes - incl. Associated Spring Corporation, 3 (Box 36)
    - Watkins Machine Co. (Box 36)
    - Materials: F. Weber Co. (Box 36)
    - Materials: S.S. White, Dental Manufacturing Co. (Box 36)
    - Materials: Whitehead Metal Products (Box 36)
  - Financial Correspondence and Material
    - Tax Returns, 1947-1981; 33 (Box 37)
    - Misc.: Unidentified Bank Check Stubs (Box 38)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank, 9 (Box 38)
    - Chemical Bank, 4 (Box 38)
    - Connecticut Savings and Connecticut National Bank (Box 38)
    - Post Office Savings Bank (Box 38)
    - Westminster Bank, 8 (Box 38)
    - Woodbury Savings Bank (Box 38)
  - Legal and Other Correspondence
    - Adler and Perowne Ltd., 3 (Box 39)
    - Ardath Tobacco Co. Ltd. (Box 39)
    - Basil Butler Co., Ltd. (Box 39)
    - Council for Industrial Design, Britain (Box 39)
    - Design Research Unit, 7 (Box 39)
    - Guild Services, 2 (Box 39)
    - O.C. Hawkes Ltd. (Box 39)
    - Imperial Airways (Box 39)
    - Jowett Cars Ltd., 7 (Box 39)
    - Ministry of Supply (Box 39)
    - Plastilume Products Ltd. (Box 39)
    - Roanoid Ltd., Glasgow, 2 (Box 39)
    - Slutsky, N. (Box 39)
    - German Patent Reichspatentamt, 2 (Box 40)
    - Korsch, T. (Box 40)
    - French Patent: Construction Elements, relating to reinforced concrete (Box 40)
    - Alexander, H.J. (Box 40)
    - British Patents: Boult Wade and Tenant, 11 (Box 40)
    - F.J. Cleveland and Co., London (Box 40)
    - Frank B. Dehn and Co. (Box 40)
    - Department of Scientific and Industrial Research (Box 40)
    - U.S. Patents: Mock and Blum, 4 (Box 40)
    - USA: Fish Richardson and Neave (Box 40)
    - The Perpetual Calendar Drawing and Explanation (Box 40)
    - Plate-Like Structures and Building Construction Units (Box 40)
    - Drawing of Ceiling Structure (Box 40)
- Writings, 1920-1975; Series II; 3.13; (8 boxes)
  Organized into three subseries: Writings of Naum Gabo, Writings About Naum Gabo, and Other Publications.
  Series II. Writings contains original writings by Gabo, most dating to the latter period of his life in the United States, such as the collection of essays on the fine arts, Of Divers Arts (1962), as well as material relating to his early The Realistic Manifesto, first published in Russia in 1920 and then in translation in 1957.
  - Writings of Naum Gabo
    - Gabo Writings Re: Bijenkor (Box 41)
    - Writings: the Realist Manifesto 1920 fragment of original MS in Russian (Box 41)
    - Writings: The Realist Manifesto, 2 (Box 41)
    - "Letter to the Editor" (Box 41)
    - "Gestaltung?/Creative Design" (Box 41)
    - Die Probleme des Raumes und der Zeit Und Ihre Fulschungen (Box 41)
    - "Synopsis of Lectures" (Box 41)
    - Gabo, Dictaphone Belt (Box 41)
    - "Construction Art", The Listener (Box 41)
    - Plus (Box 41)
    - Focus (Box 41)
    - World Review (Box 41)
    - Synopsis for Monogram to be Published by Poetry London (Box 41)
    - Esso Building (Box 41)
    - Final Page of Gabo's Yale Lecture (Box 41)
    - Schwitters (Box 41)
    - Gabo's Questionnaire for his students at Harvard (Box 41)
    - "A New Construction for Baltimore" Magazine of Art (Box 41)
    - Baltimore Construction - Gabo's Dedication (Box 41)
    - "Art and Science" (Box 41)
    - Aphorism concerning his approach to the machine (Box 41)
    - "Notes about La Chatte" (Box 41)
    - Notes for Spheric Theme (Box 41)
    - Commentary on the Productivist Manifesto, "The Programme of the First Working Group of Constructivists" (Box 41)
    - Lecture on Constructive Realism (Box 41)
    - Text for Tape Recording made for the Arts Council of Great Britain by Nikki Ventris (Box 41)
    - Gabo Talks About His Work (Box 41)
    - Buffalo-Albright Knox Art Gallery, Gabo Lecture (Box 41)
    - Concerning the Reconstruction of Kinetic Construction (Box 41)
    - Starr-Frampton Interview Material (Box 41)
    - Mark Toby (Box 41)
    - Peter Lanyon (Box 41)
    - BBC Film material (Box 41)
    - Gabo Interview - Text of BBC Film by John Read, 3 (Box 41)
    - Interview 1973 for Christian Science Monitor with Susan Littlewood (Box 41)
    - Princeton Lecture Spring 1975 (Box 41)
    - Untitled essay on art and technology (Box 41)
    - Assorted notes in Gabo's hand in Russian and English (Box 41)
    - 1957 Monograph (Box 42)
    - Of Divers Arts (Box 42)
    - Of Divers Arts, illustrations (Box 42)
    - Of Divers Arts, page proofs, 3 (Box 42)
    - Of Divers Arts, typescript (Box 42)
  - Writings About Naum Gabo
    - Alexei Pevsner's Book, 9 (Box 43)
    - W. Sandberg - Introduction to Alexei Pevsner's Book (Box 43)
    - Gabo Bibliography (Box 44)
    - Brandt, M. and Kallai, E.: "Bauhausstil" (Box 44)
    - S. Chermayeff: "Naum Gabo" (Box 44)
    - Cornford, Christopher: Text for Gabo Exhibition Catalogue (Box 44)
    - K.G. Hulten: "Re Naum Gabo's First Sculptures", 2 (Box 44)
    - Ernst Kallai: "Der Plastiker Gabo", 2 (Box 44)
    - Herbert Read: "Gabo" (Box 44)
    - Herbert Read: piece for the Albright-Knox Art Gallery, Buffalo Exhibition (Box 44)
    - Herbert Read: "The Art of Naum Gabo and Antoine Pevsner" (Box 44)
    - Herbert Read: "Painting Personality and Purpose" (Box 44)